Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Your Majesties, Lady Cao brought
Princess Wenyi here to pay respects.
Bringing the princess here on such a hot day
could cause excessive internal heat.
Show her in quickly.
Grace to Your Majesties.
The sun is ablaze at this hour.
Why did you come out with the princess?
Even if you are able to endure it, can she?
Your Majesty is right.
However, the princess was crying all morning.
I thought she must be missing Her Majesty.
[The empress is the formal mother of all imperial children.]
Never mind. I haven't seen Wenyi for some time, either.
Come here, I will hold her.
She feels lighter than she was a few days ago.
She hasn't been eating a lot lately.
The hot weather weakens her appetite.
Wenyi is still young and vulnerable to the heat.
I'm afraid the concubines are struggling as well.
It's been sweltering.
How about we move to the
Summer Palace to escape the heat?
The Summer Palace is regularly maintained.
Your Majesty can depart at any time.
I'd like to stay there for a while.
It has been the mourning period for the prior emperor,
so I haven't been there for two years.
Moving there is not difficult.
But the Summer Palace cannot accommodate all the concubines.
Which ones should accompany Your Majesty?
These two without doubt.
The mothers of the princes and princesses
will follow to take care of their children.
And Concubine Estime. That will be all.
Consort Honnête has the weakest health.
She should go with us for recuperation
instead of staying in the palace.
(sigh) Of course.
As for Consort Fleur...
I suggest that she stay to take care of
the remaining concubines in the palace.
This hairpin ...
I remember this was my gift to Consort Fleur.
Yes.
The princess was always happy to see
Her Highness wearing this hairpin.
So Her Highness gave it to me to play with Wenyi.
Consort Fleur will go as well.
Certainly.
Whose mind was so considerate
to have arranged all this for me?
My Lady, His Majesty knows you like having your room scented
but wishes to avoid burning incense in the summer heat.
Therefore, at His Majesty's behest, we arranged
flowers and the rotating fan for you, My Lady.
What a sweet and cooling breeze!
The rotating fan is exclusive to you
among all the concubines, My Lady.
What an ingenious design!
His Majesty devoted so much thought.
When it gets into the San Fu days [the hottest days],
ice will be sent here from the ice house.
It will waft gentle coolness to delight your heart.
His Majesty has already ordered us to send you ice
immediately if you feel hot, My Lady.
We will be most diligent in accommodating your needs.
Thank you for your hard work, Mr Huang.
May I trouble you to inform His Majesty that
I will visit him shortly to thank him in person?
With the greatest pleasure, My Lady.
But I'm afraid His Majesty
is going to practice mounted archery soon.
Perhaps you want to have some rest and go at a later time.
Mounted archery at this hour?
Who will His Majesty go with?
Noble Prince Guo and Lady Cao.
Lady Cao?
Yes. Princess Wenyi has been feeling better.
His Majesty wished to see them.
I always heard that His Majesty is very fond of the Summer Palace.
This is my first time here!
My Lady, I heard that Consort Honnête came as well.
We have never seen Her Highness.
Consort Honnête has been bed-ridden for years.
We will get to see her sooner or later.
What is that?
What exceptional archery!
The wild pigeons in west Beijing are known for their swiftness.
But the archer shot two pigeons through four eyes with one arrow.
Peace to Lady Sourire.
Is it His Majesty who is practicing archery?
Noble Prince Guo came to visit.
His Lordship is hunting casually with His Majesty.
The true Noble Prince Guo.
Vermilion told me that His Majesty pretended
to be Noble Prince Guo when he first met you in the garden.
Now we have the real person here.
His Majesty has excellent archery skills.
It was Noble Prince Guo.
His Majesty was also full of praise for His Lordship.
Noble Prince Guo is known
for his achievement in the four arts.
It's a surprise that he excels at archery too.
Miss, you'll discover more of His Lordship's
versatility as you stay longer in the palace. use of "miss"
Xiao-Xiazi, you should bring back
the pigeons quickly.
And please inform His Majesty that I will pay respects
to him when he returns to the Governance Hall.
I take my leave, My Lady.
I remember that Father taught you archery personally.
Your Majesty's archery shifu was
the greatest baturu [Machu warrior].
Even though Father taught me,
my dull mind did not learn the true skills.
What barturu taught was archery skills;
what Father gave was his affection.
Father was always more nurturing toward you.
"Before conferring great responsibilities on a man,
Heaven first suffers his mind to hardship and adversities."
It's precisely because of Father's indulgence
that I ended up becoming a useless person.
You've had a long day.
You should go have some rest.
I shall return to the Governance Hall.
His Majesty departs.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
You've arrived.
Through significant effort, my seventeenth brother managed to acquire this half catty of "snow-topped jade".
It is such fine tea.
You should try some.
You Majesty seems to be in a great mood.
I heard that the "snow-topped jade" can only
be found on dangerous precipices in the cold far north.
There are hardly more than a dozen trees
of the kind in the world.
Nourished by the snow,
the tea has a refreshingly crisp taste.
His Lordship is very devoted!
- Xiao-Xiazi.
- Aye.
Most impressively, it takes significant effort
to deliver the tea here safely in such hot weather.
The thought is rarer than the gift itself.
His Majesty was just saying how he would be
concerned about the costs if he received the tea every year.
While His Lordship is a thoughtful person,
Your Majesty thinks for the greater good.
Lady Sourire, you are right on point.
I heard that Your Majesty had just
completed a rewarding hunt with His Lordship.
I wonder why His Lordship has disappeared already.
Sourire, His Lordship must have heard of your supernal beauty,
so he has to avoid meeting you.
I am immensely flattered.
Your Majesty need not cover up for His Lordship.
His Lordship must have known that
I look like Wuyan, the ugly woman of Qi.
So he left to dodge the fright.
Did you hear that?
If she looked like Wuyan, wouldn't my entire harem
be written as ugly women in history?
Sourire said it in jest.
She was just being humble.
Try some "snow-topped jade".
This is truly good tea.
It has a refreshing taste and subtle aroma.
What a thoughtful gift from Lord XVII!
I was told that when Your Majesty first met Lady Sourire,
you approached her using Lord XVII's name
and conversed with her about flute playing.
That was the start of your conjugal happiness today.
What a romantic tale in the palace.
Even such a delicate secret is know to you, Lady Cao.
You must have heard it from His Majesty.
I didn't say anything.
Qinmo has an attentive ear and heard the story.
In that case, Lord XVII is the
matchmaker for Your Majesty and Sourire.
You should thank His Lordship.
This Lord Matchmaker
is well-known for his unrestrained charm.
Many ladies from the distinguished families in court
admire and desire His Lordship.
Sourire, I believe you must have heard of
His Lordship's name in your maiden years.
Before I entered the palace, I spent my maiden years in seclusion,
and I was quarantined after entering the palace.
I had never heard about His Lordship.
How shallow and ignorant of me.
His Majesty possesses heavenly literary talents
and the most considerate mind towards the concubines.
I wonder if His Majesty did the same
when approaching your aroma and beauty, Lady Cao.
Wenyi must be feeling hungry at this hour.
Please allow me to leave and check on her.
All right.
Wenyi is still crying a lot after she got better.
Ask Dr. Jiang to take a look
when he visits you for routine pulse-taking.
Certainly, I will report to Your Majesty after Dr. Jiang visits.
This zither is a treasured item
of the prior emperor's Consort Serein.
I was craving for some zither music before you arrived.
But Lady Cao was just as apt as
her name Qinmo [a quiet lyre].
Her skills were quite rusty.
Your Majesty, what about I send for Meizhuang?
She is a brilliant zither player.
Meizhuang is more proficient in the craft than you are,
but her playing somewhat lacks emotions.
Emotionless music, even played from
such a fine zither, is dull and insipid.
Will you play the zither for me?
With pleasure, Your Majesty.
What an excellent instrument!
The sound is so crisp and clear.
The jade-colored water and tea;
the refreshing breeze and zither playing.
Such is a pleasure of life.
Let's hear the first verse of Ode to Mountain Living.
My playing was inept.
I hope I did not incur Your Majesty's ridicule.
Your playing was exquisite.
It's just that you were distracted.
You did not devote your whole heart to the zither.
I beg Your Majesty's forgiveness
for my failure to commit to the zither.
It was your first time playing the zither.
I understand that you were unacquainted with it.
But I have another question in mind.
Your affection for me - I can clearly perceive.
But I want to know when you began to have feelings for me.
What I see is the person sitting before me
regardless of his name or title.
What do you mean?
When Your Majesty used the name of Noble Prince Guo
to discuss music with me in the garden,
although I admired your knowledge and flair,
I kept a respectful distance and behaved with proprieties
knowing that you were a lord.
After Your Majesty revealed your identity,
you showed generous care for me
and treated me differently from the other concubines.
That is why I not only see Your Majesty
as my monarch, but also as my husband.
If I must tell Your Majesty the exact time,
it was when Your Majesty helped me
when I was cornered by Yu in the garden.
I was shocked and flustered at that moment.
While it was as easy as lifting a finger for Your Majesty,
in my eyes, Your Majesty was the Noble Man
who rescued me from distress.
I was just asking casually.
I hope Your Majesty will allow me to finish.
Saying this may be a capital offense to Your Majesty:
I do revere you as my monarch,
but even above that, I regard you as my loving husband.
I have always known your feelings.
That is why I hold you dear to my heart.
Huan Huan, I was overly suspicious today.
Don't blame me.
Si Lang.
My Lady, do you suspect that someone revealed
your secret to Lady Cao?
It is only a suspicion that I have.
I have no evidence.
But only people who are closest to you
would know this story.
I wasn't aware of it until today.
I believe Vermilion was the only witness in the garden.
But she is a dowry maid of yours, My Lady.
I know.
But Vermilion has been with me for so many years.
I have confidence in her.
Indeed.
She would never collude with Cao Qinmo against me.
I agree, My Lady.
Vermilion... is quick-tongued.
She might have carelessly mentioned it to someone else.
But her unintentional words fell on a purposeful ear
and consenquently were passed on to Lady Cao.
That might be the only way to explain it.
It was fortunate that His Majesty trusted me.
"The rumor of a tiger spread three times is more dangerous
than the tiger itself."
That is true.
You've earned His Majesty's trust.
That is more important than anything else.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
At Your Majesty's behest, I have instructed the
Imperial Kitchen to reduce the food ration for every palace
and use more vegetables instead of meat.
Very well. I must set an example
as His Majesty requires frugality in the harem.
Certainly.
Consort Fleur and Consort Astuce are high in rank -
they have to do the same
so that the other concubines will readily follow suit.
Your Majesty is wise.
It was not my wisdom.
It was Lady Shen who proposed the idea
to cut the ration before His Majesty.
I must not take credit for her thought and effort.
Your Highness, I brought you
some desserts from the Imperial Kitchen.
It's one thing to have fewer desserts,
but why didn't they prepare the crab puffs that I like?
The kitchen staff said that crab powder is very expensive.
The Empress has decreed that
they stop making such pricey desserts.
Not only has she halved the daily ration,
she's even so stingy about the desserts?
Your Highness, please don't be mad.
The Summer Palace is not as well-provided as the Forbidden City.
The Empress is always stingy.
You can count the concubines here on one hand.
How much can we possibly expend?
Our lunch and dinner are both vegetarian now.
A needle mushroom salad after pickled cucumbers.
Not a single dish even looked like meat!
My appetite is already ruined by the summer heat.
There's no point in eating at all!
I learned that it is the same in the Empress's palace.
It was all Lady Shen's idea. She suggested
to His Majesty that we halve the food ration.
She's not yet managing the palace affairs,
but already "waving a chicken feather like a commander's arrow."
- Songzhi.
- Yes.
Distribute some money among the servants.
Now that every palace is on a budget,
the servants will appreciate additional provisions.
Lunar made me this new sour prune soup.
It tastes better than what the Imperial Kitchen makes.
You should try some!
You forgot that I don't like sour food, didn't you?
Oh, my poor memory.
In that case, I'll have yours.
My Lady, you've had four or five servings already.
It might cause stomach pain.
All right then.
I just couldn't help drinking it on a hot day.
Poria is very good at making prune soup.
Who is Poria?
She's a maid in the Summer Palace.
She was sent to serve My Lady.
Princess Wenyi will have her
first birthday on the 19th of next month.
His Majesty has asked the Empress
to hold a grand celebration for her.
His Majesty has been seeing Lady Cao
more lately because of Wenyi.
The incident with Consort Fleur did not affect her
so she has seemed more confident recently.
Yes, I heard about what happened two days ago.
She aroused suspicion in His Majesty with just a few words.
She's not someone to be underestimated.
Fortunately, His Majesty didn't bring it up again.
No matter what place we hold His Majesty's favor at present,
it is not secure until we produce an heir.
Consort Fleur is one good example.
Even though she was dominant in the harem,
she was deprived of her authority overnight.
Without a child in your arms, everything else is futile in the palace.
You are different from them.
Indeed, I am different from them.
His Majesty dislikes Consort Astuce but still
talks to her for the sake of the Third Prince.
Same with Lady Cao and Attendant Joie.
His Majesty adores their daughters just as dearly.
As long as His Majesty cares for the child,
the mother will also be cherished.
Otherwise, a concubine will be forgotten after
the His Majesty's affection fades and vanishes.
By my calculations, it has been almost a year
since your first service to His Majesty.
I wonder ... why we still haven't heard the good news.
His Majesty hardly visits the harem.
Now that I'm helping Her Majesty with the palace affairs.
I have even less time to myself.
I suppose I must lack Heaven's blessings.
Nonsense, it has nothing to do with that.
Consort Fleur was in high favor
even though she never had a child.
We're still young, there's plenty of time ahead.
We'll certainly have many children to fill the rooms with joy.
Put your mind at ease, Meizhuang.
Can I talk to you heart-to-heart?
Although conceiving Heaven's heir depends on the will of Heaven,
"people propose while Heaven disposes."
There is something... we can work on.
All that matters is whether His Majesty visits...
What is there for us to do?
May I help you, doctor?
My name is Liu Ben. I'm here for the routine pulse-taking
because Dr. Jiang is away for a family funeral.
Dr. Liu, I hope you won't mind waiting for a while.
My Lady is talking to Lady Sourire.
Certainly.
I used both soft and hard tactics to finally get
Dr. Jiang agree to give me this prescription.
Following his instructions,
the conception of a boy is guaranteed.
You should take the prescription as well.
Who is this Dr. Jiang?
Who else can it be?
Dr. Jiang Cheng. He's an expert in gynecology.
Jiang Cheng?
His younger brother, Jiang Shen,
is the doctor of Lady Cao and her daughter.
Exactly.
Can we trust his prescription?
Don't worry.
I wasn't sure about him and sent many people
to investigate his background extensively.
Jiang Cheng and Jiang Shen are half-brothers
and their mothers are on competitive terms.
So the two brothers also clash like fire and water.
That is why I trust him.
Rest assured and use it.
I also read many medical books
before I decided to use his prescription.
But I can't help feeling skeptical.
Put the prescription aside for now.
Wait until you've asked Dr. Wen.
Vermilion, can you make the trip
to see if Dr. Wen is on shift today?
If so, bring him here right away.
My Lady, Lord Protector Sun is gravely ill.
Dr. Wen was sent away to attend to him.
He will stay there day and night
and won't return until Lord Sun recovers.
When did Dr. Wen go?
Yesterday afternoon.
Dr. Wen left on short notice
because it was an emergency.
How unfortunate!
Don't worry about it. I've had two doses already.
I trust it is fine.
You don't need to summon a brigade for it.
We don't need to bring Dr. Wen all the way here.
I see a doctor is waiting in the courtyard.
I shall go now since a doctor is visiting you.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Vermilion.
Your servant bows in respect before Mistress.
The humble doctor bows in respect before My Lady.
This doctor looks very new to the eye.
I don't remember seeing you before.
This is my first visit to you, My Lady.
You seem to have a Jizhou accent.
I was transferred from Jizhou just a few days ago.
What serendipity.
I'm from Jizhou as well.
I feel deeply honored, My Lady.
Poria, brew a pot of Dragon Well tea.
Yes.
Princess Wenyi will be one year old in half a month.
We don't have many children in the palace.
The first birth anniversary is worth a grand celebration.
Although we are in the Summer Palace,
His Majesty wishes not to simplify the ceremony.
We must make it lively and memorable.
I have instructed the Household Department
to prepare for the occasion.
I thank Your Majesties.
Wenyi and I are eternally thankful.
Producing an heir is a contribution to the imperial family.
There's no need to thank us.
Having many imperial heirs is a blessing for all under Heaven.
His Majesty doesn't have many children.
I hope every one of you can ease the worry of His Majesty.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Although we don't have many imperial heirs,
we do get one more whenever we come to the Summer Palace.
Consort Fleur, don't speak of such a taboo subject.
I don't care if that's a taboo to anyone.
How can the son of a humble maid
be counted as an imperial heir?
While the mother of the Fourth Prince was a humble maid,
he is still the son of His Majesty
and equally the brother of the Third Prince.
Ha. Equal?
All right. Why did you bring this up out of nowhere?
We all have been serving His Majesty for a long time.
Even if you don't care about it being a palace taboo,
do you not care about His Majesty's feelings?
I dare not, Your Majesty.
When you are able, you must help the Third Prince review his studies
in case His Majesty inquires.
I thank Your Majesty for caring.
The Third Prince has been diligent,
working into late nights recently.
Very well, he must set
a good example as His Majesty's eldest son.
What's the point of working hard?
It hasn't made him better than a low-born child.
I heard the Fourth Prince reciting
poems by the lake on my way here.
He sounded much more fluent than his elder brother.
Your Majesty, his mother Li Jingui died a long time ago.
I wonder has been taking care of the Forth Prince
so that he is smarter than his distinguished thrid brother?
You...
Consort Fleur, don't forget your manners.
Lady Cao, as Princess Wenyi is turning one year old,
you should be promoted to a higher rank in principle.
But His Majesty said we are on a budget,
faced with potential outbreaks of warfare.
His Majesty wishes to hold a
glorious ceremony for you after quelling the wars.
I believe you won't mind the delay.
Certainly, Your Majesty.
I am truly grateful for His Majesty's thoughtfulness.
But I'm too humble to such heavenly grace from His Majesty.
My only wish is to always serve by Your Majesties' side.
I know you always consider the greater good.
His Majesty granted Wenyi a pair of jade ruyi to place her pillow on.
I will have it sent to your palace later.
I thank Your Majesty.
Madam Autumn!
My Lord! Why did you come here?
Where are your maids?
They haven't been looking after me.
May I pay respect to Her Majesty?
Her Majesty is having a nap.
May I pay respect to Imperial Father?
You should go when His Majesty summons you, right?
Guards.
Escort the Fourth Prince back to his residence.
Yes. Please come, Forth Prince.
Your Majesty, peeling lotus seeds
might hurt your fingernails.
I know His Majesty likes lotus seeds,
so I'm peeling them myself.
I will make lotus seed soup with lily root for His Majesty.
Your Majesty's love for His Majesty
is more precious than gold.
But love is not as important as having a child.
Your Majesty, the Fourth Prince stopped by.
Why did he come here?
He wished to see His Majesty.
Forget it. He'll only remind His Majesty of the past troubles.
His Majesty would be displeased.
The Fourth Prince lost his birth mother young.
He is quite pitiful, being here all alone.
Are you suggesting that I foster the Fourth Prince?
I was thinking the Fourth Prince might be an option
if Your Majesty wanted "a filial child serving at your knees."
But he is His Majesty's least favored child.
What's the use of fostering him? Don't bother.
The hot and humid weather has caused pimples.
Look, here's one, and here's another.
Don't worry. Now that you have two pimples,
they increase the rosiness of your fair skin.
You were having pimples a few days ago.
Now that they're gone, you start to make fun of mine.
All right, I'll stop.
I can give you the formula if you like.
It was a folk remedy offered by Dr. Liu Ben,
who happens to be from Jizhou as well.
That is why my pimples were cured so quickly.
But I've never heard of this doctor.
He was just transferred from Jizhou.
He is a skilled doctor.
It is always nice to know
someone from your hometown.
Is he trustworthy?
I think so, he's reliable.
That's good.
When it comes to selecting doctors,
their character matters more than skills.
We must ensure that they have a clear background.
I agree.
Now that we have Dr. Wen Shichu and Dr. Liu Ben,
they will complement each other in medicine.
Since you trust this doctor,
did you ask him to review Dr. Jiang's prescription?
Yes, he said it is a perfect formula.
Really?
Peace to Your Highness.
I thought that only the three of us were strolling in the garden.
Lady Sourire and Lady Shen are out here as well.
It's nice that the weather is cooler now.
I'm glad to see you here, Sourire.
I was planning to pay you a visit later.
Cao, I wonder if there is anything I can do for you.
I made an improper remark the other day.
I heard that it caused discord between you and His Majesty.
I had no intention of doing that.
I must ask for your forgiveness now that I've seen you.
It was nothing like that, Lady Cao.
I simply exchanged banter with His Majesty.
It was nothing serious.
His Majesty is very fond of Lady Sourire.
Bantering with His Majesty is all too common for her.
But it would be such a big deal if it was someone else.
How can we possibly compare to Lady Sourire?
We first must be able to see His Majesty
before we can banter with him.
All right, all right.
We shouldn't be all standing here for a talk.
How about we all go to my place?
I've had food prepared to apologize to Sourire.
And I invited Consort Astuce
and Attendant Joie for this purpose.
I hope you will not decline, Sourire.
Lady Shen,
I've heard of your talent for playing the zither.
It's said that "An entertaining host attracts visitors."
But I am such an inept hostess;
I have no such talent.
So I hope Lady Shen won't mind
helping me entertain my guests with your music.
I'm grateful for your invitation, Lady Cao.
My Lady, the prune drink has cooled down.
We've brought some for everyone.
You brought on the refreshing drink
after the greasy dishes.
What a thoughtful hostess we have!
What is wrong, Lady Shen?
I probably had more pork rind jelly than I should have.
I'm feeling a little nauseous now.
Nauseous?
But you were fine just a moment ago.
Have you been feeling nauseous recently?
I haven't been eating well the past week due to the summer heat.
Ah?
Is that ... because of pregnancy?
Have you received your "monthly letters"?
I ...
Aiya, we are sisters. Don't be shy.
- You can tell us.
- Exactly.
It's been late for more than half a month.
She's very likely to be with child.
What does Your Highness think, Consort Astuce?
In addition to feeling nauseous,
have you been feeling lethargic lately?
And ... and having a craving for spicy food?
Xiao-Weizi, send for the doctors immediately.
Yes.
Make sure to bring Dr. Liu Ben.
Grace to Your Majesty.
You were the first to arrive, nonetheless.
Is it true that Lady Shen is pregnant?
I was just informed. I don't know the details.
To be thorough, I have ordered the Attendance Service
to send their records here immediately.
- Let's go inside together.
- Certainly.
His Majesty the Emperor.
- Peace to Your Majesties.
- Sit down, sit down.
Is it true?
Doctor, can you confirm whether Lady Shen is pregnant?
Congratulations to Your Majesty and My Lady!
Lady Shen is indeed pregnant, for over a month.
Very well. All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Autumn, bring me the registry.
Here, Your Majesty.
(Palace of Universal Happiness, Lady Shen,
9 pm to 3 am, 16th day of the third month)
It was a good date.
Who are the personal maids of Lady Shen?
Your Majesty.
As Lady Shen's personal maids, you must
take more care in everything now that she's pregnant.
Report to me daily on her diet and health.
Yes.
The Empress is always meticulous.
Your Majesty, now that Lady Shen is with child,
should we select an experienced doctor to attend to her?
Your Majesty, Dr. Liu Ben came here to take my pulses.
He is a reliable doctor,
and from my hometown Jizhou as well.
Why don't we let him look after me?
Just as well.
Nothing matters more than your health.
You must ensure the best care of yourself.
Don't let anything go amiss.
Yes.
My apologies to Your Majesties.
I forgot to serve Your Majesties tea all this time.
I was overwhelmed with joy.
I feel like a drink as well.
Would you like something to drink?
I spilled some prune soup earlier.
I'm craving for it now...
Quick, quick.
Yes, of course! There is plentiful prune soup.
I will have the drink sent to you every day if you like!
Lady Cao is very kind and virtuous.
Maids, serve the prune soup?
I hope Your Majesties will like the drink as well.
Lady Sourire doesn't enjoy sour food.
Add more sugar to hers.
Yes.
I thank Your Majesty.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.